AUSTIN THALDORF-HUELSBECK - WEB DEVELOPER

SEATTLE, WA | 206-451-3834 | austinthaldorfhuelsbeck@gmail.com | Linkedin | GitHub | Portfolio

SUMMARY

Full-Stack software engineer proficient in Javascript/Typescript for front-end and back-end programming, React, HTML, CSS, API design, Node, Express, PostgreSQL, and tools like Git and Bash. My approach to development is informed by over ten years of professional experience in IT and audio engineering.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Software: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Typescript, React.js, Node.js, Express, RESTful APIs, PostgreSQL Tools: Knex, React Custom Hooks, Redux, Git, GitHub, Vercel, npm, Bash, VS Code, Data Structures Additional Skills: Windows System Administration, Powershell, Adobe CC, digital audiovisual engineering

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING PROJECTS

Full-Stack Web App - Website Builder: | Link | Details

10/2023

- Full stack single-page app developed for real-world business needs.
- Applied Express router and controller functions alongside React to display and modify content.
- Applied software development principles to deploy the application and maintain the code.
- Used tools like Git and Autho to protect the security of sensitive information.
- Technology: Typescript, React, Node.js, Express, Knex and PostgreSQL.

Full-Stack Web App - Restaurant Reservation: | Link | Details

05/2021

- Full stack reservation and table management system. Final capstone project for Thinkful Certificate..
- Leveraged React Router to create a seamless single-page app that makes complex requests.
- Implemented Express to build a RESTful API to make HTTP requests on a PostgreSQL database.
- Technology: React, Node.js, Express, Knex and PostgreSQL.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

The Seattle School Seattle, WA

Systems Administrator

08/2022 - present

- Maintained technology systems, network, ERP, and hardware, ensuring productivity and security.
- Led data migration of major financial system resulting in significant savings and increased efficiency.
- Took ownership as sole IT employee through managing vendors, licensing, and security standards.

Digital Multimedia Specialist

11/2018 - 07/2021

- Led the development of a video marketing campaign resulting in record-breaking donations.
- Grew the listenership of a branded podcast to over 3 million downloads through continuously monitoring and improving production and distribution strategies.

Austin + Emily Creative

Seattle, WA

Videographer, Co-Founder

07/2018 - present

- Launched a small business and grew to profitability, leveraging digital marketing and analyzing data.
- Built a portfolio of 25+ wedding collections utilizing state-of-the-art equipment and editing software.
- Implemented automated CRM workflows and business operations to speed up delivery.

EDUCATION

Thinkful

Online

12/2020 - 07/2021

Certificate, Software Engineering

Learned industry best practices and software development standards with a focus on Javascript,

- HTML5, CSS3, React.js, Node.js, PostgreSQL, RESTful APIs, algorithms and data structures.
- Developed and deployed mobile-first applications while learning new languages and frameworks, spending several hours per week collaborating with and learning from senior web developers in a mentor-student relationship.

George Fox University Newberg, OR